Boy?
（リカード･ウェルキン）
兄ちゃん
This can't be...
（ナツキ･スバル）まさ か…
What's wrong?
どうした？
（フェリックス･アーガイル）ハム
ハム
（スバル）ああっ！
You were spacing out, so I couldn't resist.
ボーっとしてるから
いたずらしたら―
Nyow that was a satisfying reaction!
にゃんてうれしい反応
Ferris?
フェリスか
Who else would I be?
ほかの誰に見えるの？
Did you inhale too much
of the White Whale's fog?
白鯨の霧でも 吸い込みすぎた？
Uh, no... I'm fine.
（スバル）
ああ いや… 大丈夫だ
That told me what I wanted to know.
今ので
聞きたいことは聞けた
That means...
つまり―
My save point was updated?
セーブポイント
更新されてくれてたか
There are a few new things
I've realized about the Witch Cult.
実は 魔女教関係のことで
新しく気づいたことが何個かある
Does anyone know of, like...
誰か知ってるか？
その… 自分の意識を
別の誰かの意識に上書きして―
a power you can use to overwrite someone's consciousness,
so that you take over their mind?
精神的に乗っ取るみたいな 力を
So what you're saying is, you think the
Sin Archbishop may have such an ability?
（ユリウス･ユークリウス）
つまり 大罪司教がそうした異能を
用いる可能性があると―
君はにらんでいる
Yeah, I call it "possession."
そうだ
俺は 憑依って呼んでるけど
奴はそれで生き延びてる
It's how he stays alive.
あちこちに顔を出す理由も
説明つくだろ
It would explain how he keeps
popping up everywhere, right?
In an old book, I saw a research
account of a similar subject.
以前 古い文献で
似たような研究を見たことがある
There is one such long forgotten magic.
すでに遺失した魔法だが―
However, the technique only
works under certain conditions.
その技術は 限られた
条件下でしか機能しない
Conditions?
条件？
Only members of the Witch Cult,
魔女教徒
and a select number of them at that,
are thought to be capable targets.
それも 限られた人員にのみ
可能な術法と推測できる
And those would be the fingers?
それが 指先ってこと？
Most likely, they are the user's spare bodies.
（ユリウス）
おそらく 自身の予備の肉体
なかなか悪趣味な趣向だ
It's quite a tasteless arrangement.
大罪司教らしい というべきかな
Though I suppose one
befitting of a Sin Archbishop.
So if the Sin Archbishop's confidants,
大罪司教の腹心
the fingers, were wiped out...
つまり 指先の殲(せん)滅
If that happened,
それが成されれば
奴の魂は 乗り移り先を失う
his soul would have nowhere to go.
And that would be the end of him.
そうなった時が
奴の最期と言えるだろう
森に潜む指先を 優先して排除し
怠惰と雌雄を決する
We should first eliminate the fingers in the forest,
and then confront Sloth directly.
That is my conclusion.
それが結論だ
I hate to burst your bubble, everyone,
but I have one more thing to add...
（スバル）
みんな あと１個だけ
言わなきゃいけないことがある
Sorry, but I don't think it's just the fingers.
ごめん 指先だけじゃなく―
I think he may be able to possess me too.
たぶん俺も 乗り移る
対象なんだけど―
What do you think I should do?
それについては
どうしたらいいと思う？
Huh?
Filthy woman!
（ボルドー）汚らわしい
Then, will you also apologize for being born?
（プリシラ･バーリエル）
生まれてきてごめんなさい
とでも 謝罪して…
You silver-haired half-elf.
銀色のハーフエルフよ
Margrave Mathers endorses
a half-devil? Utter foolishness!
ざれ言だ
This is a mockery!
Then, will you also apologize for being born?
You know, I had hopes for you.
（エミリア）
私ね 期待してたの
Filthy woman!
I thought maybe you...
ひょっとしたら スバルは私を―
That only you wouldn't
give me special treatment.
特別扱いしないんじゃないかって
I can't do that.
（スバル）そんなの無理だ
I can't look at you the way I look at others.
君だけは―
ほかの人間と同じ目で
見ることなんて―
It's impossible.
できっこない
I have no connection to the witch...
（エミリア）
私は 魔女と関係なんて…
You silver-haired half-elf.
Margrave Mathers endorses a half-devil?
Lia...
（パック）リア
Your forehead is all wrinkled.
眉間にしわが寄ってるよ
Good morning, Puck.
（エミリア）
おはよう パック
今日は早いのね
You're up early today.
Morning, Lia.
（パック）おはよう リア
I thought I'd give the whole
"Early to bed, early to rise" thing a shot.
早寝早起きを心がけようと思って
Well, just kidding.
というのはウソ
The truth is that I was worried about you.
本当のところは
リアが心配だったからだよ
You've had it rough lately.
大変続きだったからね
特に 昨日は
Especially yesterday...
It was nothing I didn't know already.
（エミリア）
分かってたことだもん
Even if you know you'll fall,
転ぶと分かってても―
when it happens, that doesn't stop it
from hurting or bleeding.
転んだら痛いし
血も出るもんだよ
What do you think I should do, Puck?
パックは どうしたらいいと思う？
No, this isn't about just me.
ううん 私だけじゃなくて―
How can I do more for everyone,
as well as get them to do more for me?
みんなのことも
もっと ちゃんとするには…
ちゃんとしてもらうには
I think you should do what you want.
リアの好きにしたら
いいんじゃないかな
I'll be on your side, no matter what you do.
僕は リアが何をしようとしても
リアの味方だし
And no matter what,
どうするにしても―
you can't abandon that village, right?
あの村のことは
見捨てられないんでしょ？
Early this morning,
Ram headed back out there.
ラムが 今朝早く
また村に向かってたから―
Maybe we should wait to hear from her.
報告を待つべきじゃないかな
ちょっと ベティーの顔を見てくる
I'm going to check on Betty.
Oh... Okay.
Let her know I said hello.
ベアトリスによろしくね
Ram?
（エミリア）ラム
Emilia-sama, you have a visitor.
（ラム）
エミリア様 お客様が
お見えになっています
あなたは… 確か
クルシュ様のところの…
You are...
from Crusch-sama's household, aren't you?
I am Wilhelm Trias.
（ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレア）
ヴィルヘルム･トリアスと申します
こたびは 主君の名代として
参じた次第
I have come on my master's behalf.
On Crusch-sama's behalf?
（エミリア）クルシュ様の？
I received a blank letter from her yesterday...
昨日 白紙の親書を
頂いたのだけど…
I see, so it was true.
なるほど やはり
While this shames me to say,
（ヴィルヘルム）
いえ 恥ずかしながら 我が主(あるじ)が―
the letter's contents conflicted
with my master's true intentions.
本来お伝えしたい内容とは
そごがございます
そう 手違いなのね
Oh... It was a mistake, then?
Yes, Emilia-sama and Ram-dono...
はい エミリア様 ならびにラム殿
We would like to evacuate those remaining in the mansion, along with the villagers.
お屋敷に残られている方々と―
村の住人には
１度避難していただく
That is Crusch-sama's will.
それが クルシュ様のご意向です
What?
森の近くに 犯罪集団が？
There's a ring of criminals near the forest?
Yes.
（ラム）
はい　すでに使者様が
お連れになった討伐隊は
The punitive force this messenger brought
is already preparing to fight the enemy.
村の付近で
敵戦力に備えています
But why would Crusch-sama do
so much to help this domain?
でも どうしてクルシュ様が―
この領地のために
力を尽くしてくれるの？
The margrave sent my master a proposal
（ヴィルヘルム）
我が主は 辺境伯より
こたびの王選における―
for an alliance with respect to the royal selection.
同盟関係を
持ちかけられております
The condition is a share of
the mining rights in Elior Forest.
条件は エリオール大森林の
採掘権の分譲
Do you understand?
お分かりいただけますか
So that's what this is about.
そういうことなのね
But evacuating all the villagers
to the capital will be difficult.
（ヴィルヘルム）
しかし 村人の全員を
王都へ避難させるのは 困難です
Half of them will go to the capital.
ひとまず 王都へ行けるのは半数
I will lead the other half to safety in the Sanctuary.
あとの半数は ラムの案内で
聖域へ避難させます
Roswaal-sama is heading there now.
ロズワール様が そちらに
向かわれていますから
O-Oh, I see...
そ… そうなんだ
Then, discussion on the matter is already over.
すっかり話し合い 終わってるんだ
But isn't there something strange about this?
でも やっぱり変じゃない？
なんだか都合がよすぎるような…
It all seems too well-timed—
Pardon me.
（スバル）失礼します！
Strange movement has been detected
from the group hiding in the forest!
森に潜んだ集団に 奇妙な動きが
We haven't a moment to waste!
（スバル）
もう 一刻の猶予もありません！
Once they make their move,
the entire region will be a sea of blood!
奴らが動き出せば
この一帯は 血の海に！
What will it be, Captain?
いかがいたしましょう 隊長
いえ 剣鬼(けんき) ヴィルヘルム殿！
No, Sword Demon Wilhelm-dono?
Emilia-sama?
エミリア様
I understand.
分かりました
ご厚意 ありがたくお受けします
I gratefully accept your kindness.
Has this been explained to the villagers?
村の人たちに説明は？
They have all already been made aware
of the situation, Emilia-sama.
（ラム）
すでに 滞りなく済んでおります
エミリア様
I see...
そう
Betty says she'll stay here.
（パック）
ベティーは残るって
Puck!
パック
Betty can't go.
（ベアトリス）
ベティーは いけないのよ
にーちゃの帰りを待ってるかしら
I suppose I'll wait here for your return.
Don't worry about me.
心配しなくていいのよ
That's what she said.
だって
Well, in Betty's case, the forbidden library
is a much safer place.
まあ ベティーの場合―
禁書庫にいるほうが
ずっと安全だしね
Besides, due to her contract,
she can't leave the mansion.
それに あの子が屋敷と
離れられないのは 契約の問題
Lia, you know that, right?
リア 分かるよね
No fair, using that as a reason...
それを理由にするの ズルい
So, since my cute little sister will be staying here,
そんなわけで 僕のかわいい妹が
残ってるから―
we don't need to do anything about the mansion.
屋敷には 何もしないほうがいい
Betty is sweet and kind,
ベティーは優しくて
甘々だけど 容赦はないからね
but she'll show no mercy.
Understood, great spirit.
（ヴィルヘルム）
心得ております 大精霊様
You should do what you want.
君は 君のしたいようにしなよ
I'm on your side, and yours alone.
僕は君の 君だけの味方だから
We will evacuate.
（エミリア）避難します
I don't want to endanger the villagers!
村の人たちを 危険な目に
遭わせたくないもの
We're ready, miss.
（ペトラ）
よろしくお願いします
お姉ちゃん
Um, I think there's been some kind of mistake.
えっと… これって
何かの間違いじゃない？
No, given the number of people and carriages,
いいえ 竜車と人数の
兼ね合いで―
we must ask you to ride with these children.
エミリア様には―
この子たちと一緒に
乗ってもらうほかにありません
しかたのない措置よ
It's a necessary measure.
Can't we put them in a different carriage?
ほかの竜車に乗せてあげられない？
この子たちだって そのほうが…
That would be better for the children—
You think no one would want to ride with you?
（スバル）
誰だって自分と乗るのは
嫌がるはず ですか？
それ その子たちに
確認したことがありますか？
Have you asked the kids how they feel about that?
Perhaps you just assume
嫌われてるんだって―
that they hate you and
wouldn't want to be around you?
嫌がられるって 勝手に
思い込んでしまっているだけでは？
That isn't...
そんなこと… 聞かなくたって
分かってるの
I don't need to ask them.
I know it's best for everyone.
それが お互いのためだって…
Six children and one dragon carriage.
子供６人 竜車は１台
If we stumble here,
ここでつまずいてちゃ 君の願いは
どうやってかなえる
how will your wish ever come true?
A-Are you...
あなたは…
What do you think, Petra?
どうだ ペトラ
Do you refuse to ride in
the same carriage as she does?
君は あのお姉さんと
一緒の竜車はどうしてもイヤか？
Of course not.
（ペトラ）
そんなことないよ
Aren't you the lady with the potato stamps?
お姉ちゃん お芋のハンコの
お姉ちゃんでしょ？
The one who came with Subaru
to watch our radio calisthenics!
いつもスバルと一緒に―
朝のラジーオ体操
見にきてくれてた
Well...
それは…
I couldn't see your face,
（ペトラ）
いつも顔は見えなかったけど―
but I always saw you having
a good time talking with Subaru!
お姉ちゃんが スバルと
楽しそうに話してるの―
見てたもん　エヘッ
Come and ride with me.
一緒に乗ろう
And me!
（ミルド）俺も！
I wanna ride with you!
（ダイン）
お姉ちゃんと一緒に行く！
Come on, let's go!
（リュカ）
早く行こうぜ！
Let's go.
Come with us!
I can't wait!
And it's gonna be pulled by a dragon! A dragon!
That's so cool!
Ram, take care of things at the Sanctuary.
（エミリア）
ラム 聖域のことはお願い
ちゃんと 村の人を守って
Be sure to protect the villagers.
You take care as well, Emilia-sama.
エミリア様も 道中お気をつけて
I need to thank you too.
あなたにも ありがとうって
お礼を言わなきゃ
Where did he go?
どこに行っちゃったの？
ハア…
（スバル）なるほど
Now I get it...
We couldn't figure out how
you guys stayed in touch.
周りとの連絡手段だけが
謎だったけど―
Those metia sure are handy, huh?
つくづく ミーティアって
便利なもんだ
You owe a heavy price for the crime
of interrupting my touching reunion with Emilia!
俺とエミリアの感動の再会を―
ジャマしてくれた
罪は重いぜ お前ら
You're...
（ケティ）お前は
Too slow.
（ヴィルヘルム）遅い
（ケティ）う…
In short, we knew you were a spy.
早い話 お前がスパイなのは
バレバレだったんだよ
How we learned that is a trade secret.
見つけた方法は 企業秘密
So we set a trap for you,
んで 魔女教の連絡役のお前に
せっかくなんで ワナを張った
the contact for the Witch Cult.
Two hours.
２時間
お前は２時間遅れの
スケジュールを 仲間に報告した
You gave your buddies a schedule
that was two hours behind.
We'll use that time to get Emilia
and the others away,
その間に エミリアたちは
外へ逃がす
crush the fingers whose locations we know,
その間に 場所の割れている
指先は潰す
and make preparations
to crush your Sin Archbishop.
その間に お前たちの司教様を
潰す準備を整える
Having your enemy one step ahead,
ready to destroy you...
何もかも 先回りされて潰される
You're about to learn firsthand
just how terrifying that is.
その恐ろしさを
存分に味わわせてやるぜ
May the blessing of the spirits be with you.
あなたたちに 精霊の祝福が
ありますように
Good luck.
ご武運を
This is what enabled you to trick
Emilia-sama and chase her off?
エミリア様をダマして
遠くへ追いやれたのは―
これのおかげだね
Don't put it that way!
言い方に気をつけろ
Even if it's accurate, it makes me sound bad!
内容一緒でも 人聞き悪すぎだろ
That robe was woven with quite an odd spell.
随分と奇妙な術式で
編まれたローブだ
It was handmade by Roswaal.
ロズワール手製の
便利グッズで―
認識疎外の術式が
編み込まれてるらしい
Apparently, a spell is woven into it
that prevents recognition.
Originally, it was Emilia's...
もともと エミリアの私物で…
盗んだわけじゃねえよ？
I didn't steal it, okay?
Hmm...
ふーん
Well, the plan to correct the mistake with
the blank letter went off without a hitch!
さーて 計画通り―
白紙の親書対策も うまくいったし
"The letter was a mistake... It was my fault"?
（ラム）
“手紙は間違い　俺が悪かった”
村の人の説得も
スバルきゅんが頑張って…
And you worked so hard to convince
the villagers, Subaru-kyun...
Please!
（スバル）頼む
Emilia... She's a girl who would love
to get along with all of you,
エミリアが―
あの子が みんなと
仲よくなれる子なんだって―
so I want you to give her the chance
to prove herself to you!
それを分かり合うための
機会を与えてほしい
I'm sure everyone has a lot they'd like to say,
みんな いろいろと言いたいことは
あるだろうけど―
but please let us protect you long
enough to give you that chance!
その機会を作るための時間を
俺たちに守らせてほしい！
（青年団長）
ああー もうしょうがない人だな
スバル様は
Jeez, you really are hopeless, Subaru-sama.
そんなに一生懸命
守ってくれるなんて言われちゃ―
If you insist on protecting us so much,
what choice do we have?
しかたないでしょ
Getting old is just awful.
（老婆）
年を取るとイヤだね
なんだか涙腺がもろくなって
I think my tear glands have weakened.
Thank you all...
ありがとな みんな
We should be thanking you, Subaru-sama.
（ムラオサ）
それは こっちのセリフですよ
スバル様
You actually moved me.
ジーンとさせてもらったし
Don't bring it back up! It's embarrassing!
掘り返すな 恥ずかしい
フフッ あとは…
That just leaves...
Welcome back! How did it go?
おかえり どうだった？
We pulled off a surprise attack
on the ones whose locations we knew.
居所が割れとる連中に奇襲やぞ
If I messed up, I'll retire.
しくじったら 傭(よう)兵引退するわ
The map did a nice job showin' the way.
案内地図 様々やな
ってことは 地図のしるしは
奴らの拠点で間違いなかったわけだ
Then the mark on the map
really was their base!
I dunno if you'd call 'em fussy or high-strung,
but whatever it is worked against 'em.
（リカード）
几帳面なんか神経質なんか
それが 裏目ったわけや
And we got what we were after.
目的のもんも このとおり
This should shut down their
communications network.
これで 奴らの連絡網は潰れたやろ
Hooray! We killed 'em all!
（ミミ･パールバトン）
ヤッハー！ 皆殺しだー
Don't say that. It makes us sound like bad guys.
（ティビー･パールバトン）
人聞き悪いこと 言わないですよ
ちゃーんと 捕虜も取りましたです
We managed to take a prisoner too!
A prisoner?
捕虜？
プッ… そいつ 魔女教じゃねえよ
He isn't in the Witch Cult...
I wondered why you hadn't shown up.
You got caught, Otto?
お前 出てこないと思ったら
捕まってたのかよ オットー
フッハハハハ…
I don't know who you are,
but thanks for saving me.
（オットー･スーウェン）
誰だか知りませんが
助けて頂いてありがとうございます
You know what, I'm really not in the mood
to say that from the heart, damn it!
って 素直に言いたくない
気分なんですが チクショウ！
（スバル）アッハッハッハ
（ユリウス）
準備は従前に整った
Everything is ready.
Subaru, we can leave at any time.
スバル いつでも行ける
やろう みんな
Let's do this, everyone.
We'll proceed as planned.
手はずどおり始める
Now...
さあ―
Let's finish this once and for all!
今度こそ 決着だ！
怠惰と運命様に
目に物見せてやろうぜ！
Let's show both Fate
and Sloth what we're made of!
I've been waiting for you, believer in love.
（ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ）
よくおいでになりました
寵(ちょう)愛の信徒よ
I am a Sin Archbishop in the Witch Cult.
私は魔女教 大罪司教―
Archbishop of Sloth,
“怠惰”担当―
Petelgeuse Romanée-Conti, at your service!
ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ―
デス！
Pleasure to meet you, great Sin Archbishop.
（スバル）
お初にお目にかかります
大罪司教様
If you could find it within you to add
my body and soul to your fingers' ranks,
この身 この魂―
こたびの試練を取り仕切る
司教様の指先―
carrying out the Ordeal,
there would be no greater honor.
その末席にお加え頂ければ
これ以上の栄誉はありません
おおーっ！ 何とすばらしく
みずみずしき信仰なのデスかー！
How wondrous, how vivacious your faith is!
To think there was such
a devout believer out there!
あなたのような敬虔(けいけん)な信徒を―
Please forgive my sloth, for failing to find him!
これまで見過ごした
私の怠惰を―
どうか お許しを お許しを
お許しを お許しを お許しをー！
Forgive me! Forgive me! Forgive me!
Forgive me! Forgive me!
Please stop, Archbishop.
おやめください 司教様
Ah... But, but, but...
（ペテルギウス）
あー しかし しかし しかし―
I have no way to atone for my sloth
and foolishness but by punishment.
私は 自らの怠惰を―
愚かしさを罰せずに償うすべを
持たないのデス
That's not true.
そんなことはありません
The witch wouldn't want to see
her beloved believer in pain.
魔女様ならば 愛すべき
信徒の傷つく姿より―
She would be happier to see
you carry out the Ordeal!
試練を遂行する在り方を
喜ばれるはずです！
カー！ 全てあなたの
おっしゃるとおりデス
You are exactly right...
そう 試練
Yes, the Ordeal.
What she needs from me now is the Ordeal!
今の私に求められるのは 試練！
Your words have opened my eyes.
あなたの言葉で 目が覚めたのデス
Thank you! Thank you!
感謝 感謝
With this Ordeal, we must test her...
試練を取り行い 試さなければ―
こたびの半魔が 器に足るか―
To learn if this half-devil is a worthy vessel,
if she is worthy to put the witch into.
魔女を降ろすに足るか 試すのデス
Put the witch into? Vessel?
魔女を降ろす 器？
合えばよし 合わねば廃止
If she is, the witch will possess her.
If not, discard her.
If she proves a worthy vessel for the witch,
魔女にふさわしき
器たらんとするならば―
then the witch will be reborn into
this world on the coming fated day.
いずれ来(きた)る運命の日にこそ
魔女はこの地に再誕せりーデス
You're saying Emilia is just an afterthought,
a convenient means to an end, to you?
つまり―
エミリア自身のことは ついでで
何の価値も見てないのか
You monster...
怪物め…
The words inscribed in the Gospel tell of her love.
福音書に記されし言葉が
愛を物語る！
All of it guides my path!
全てが私を導くのデス！
Show me your Gospel.
福音の提示を
ん？ それは？
What is that?
Just what it looks like. A metia, dear Archbishop.
（スバル）
見てのとおり
ミーティアです 司教様
あっ 映った映った
Oh, I see him! I see him!
あ！ 聞いてたとおりに怖い顔
His face looks just as scary as I'd heard!
Exactly who are you?
一体 あなたは…
No! Who are you people!?
えー！ あなた方は何を！
Now, then... Tora, Tora, Tora.
では トラ トラ トラ！
Our surprise attack is a success!
ワレ奇襲ニ成功セリー
What?
な！ くっ くく… 奇襲… 奇襲…
Surprise attack... Surprise attack...
Then, what do you think of this!?
ならば これはいかがデスー！
How? How can you see my Authority!?
なぜ なぜ 我が権能が
見えているのデスかー！
Who knows?
さあ
俺の体に残り香いっぱい付けてく
魔女に聞いてくれよ
Ask the witch that left her scent all over me.
Oh, that's right.
おっと 俺と違って お前は―
Unlike me, you haven't received the pass
that lets you meet the witch anytime.
自由に魔女と面会できる許可証は
もらってないんだったかなー
はあ それは どういう…
What do you mean?
How dare you speak as though you
are intimate with the witch!
魔女に親しくしたような
不敬な発言を！
We're so close, she's grabbed my heart.
ハートをぎゅっとつかまれた仲だよ
Literally.
文字どおり
I-Inconceivable!
あああ ありえないー！
That cannot be!
あってはならないのデス！
行くぜ パトラッシュ！
Let's go, Patrasche!
逃げられるなどと
思わないことデス
Do not presume you can escape.
Here he comes, here he comes, here he comes!
来た来た来た来た
来てる来てる来てる！
He's coming, he's coming, he's coming!
Keep it up, Patrasche!
パトラッシュ 頑張って！
Futile! Impossible!
（ペテルギウス）ムダ！ 無理！
Vanish in the face of my diligence!
我が身の勤勉さの前に
かき消えるがいいデス！！
Sorry to always rely on you.
頼ってばっかりで すまねえ
お前は最高だ パトラッシュ！
You're the best, Patrasche!
But... But, but, but...
（ペテルギウス）
しかーし しかししかし
しかし しかーし！
But!
This is the end, the end!
ここまでまでだ！
お前ら… 今 俺のこと
巻き込むとこだったぞ！
You guys...
You almost caught me in that!
Thanks, though. I thought I was a goner.
でも ありがとう
死んじゃうかと思った！
You're welcome! Yay!
どういたしまして イエーイ！
Is that man in the sky the Sin Archbishop?
空の上にいるのが
大罪司教ですです？
Yikes! What the heck is that!?
（ミミ）
えー！ 何あれ スゴ！
There's a man flying, all balled up! Wow!
丸まったおっさん 飛んでる！
えー スゴ！
I've never seen anything so creepy in flight.
あんな気持ち悪い飛び方
初めて見たです
That's how it looks to you guys?
お前らには そういう風に
見えてんのか
Either way, leave him to me.
どっちにしろ
あいつの相手は任せろ
Watch the rear, like we planned!
手はずどおり 後ろを頼む！
分かりましたです
行くですよ お姉ちゃん！
Got it!
You heard him, Sis!
Aye-aye!
あいあーい！
Hey, Bro.
お兄さん―
Beat him now, and you'll look awesome!
ここで勝ったら かっこいいぞ！
Yeah, I got this!
おう 任せとけ！
Bring it on, Archbishop!
来いよ 司教様！
Who...
あなたは あなたは一体
一体 何をー！
Just who... Who are you!?
そんなはずがない！
福音書には―
That cannot be.
None of this is in the Gospel,
in the guide to my destiny!
我が運命の導きには
何も記されていないのデスー！
Who... Just who are you?
あなたは… あなたは一体 何を！
You've asked that four times now.
４回 繰り返してきたよ
悪夢なら 俺のほうが死ぬほど見た
If we're talking nightmares,
I've had far more than you.
Then... Then, then... You truly are Pride's...
やはり やはりやはり―
あはたは“傲慢”の…
My name is Natsuki Subaru,
俺の名前は ナツキ･スバル
銀髪のハーフエルフ
エミリアの騎士だ
the silver-haired half-elf Emilia's knight.
（ペテルギウス）ギイー！
I don't know anything about this "Pride" stuff,
but that's the only title I want.
（スバル）
傲慢だか何だか知らねえが―
俺の欲しがる看板は
それだけで―
I don't need any others.
あとは いらねえよ
This place is...
この場所は…
It's a place where my time once ended.
（スバル）
一度 俺が
終わったことのある場所だ
And it will be where your time ends too.
そんでもって―
お前にとっても
終わりの場所になる―
That's what this place is.
そういう場所だ
If your goal was to lead me out here,
ここまで誘い込むのが
あなたの狙いであれば―
what have you prepared for me?
何を用意したのデスか？
What else? Your natural enemy.
決まってる 天敵だよ
One you and I have in common...
俺とお前の共通の
"Natural enemy"?
天敵とは また随分と
言ってくれるものだ
Now, that's a fine thing to call me.
ルグニカ王国 近衛(このえ)騎士団所属
ユリウス･ユークリウス
I am Julius Juukulius,
of the Lugunica Imperial Knights.
I am the Kingdom's sword that will slay you.
貴様を切る 王国の剣(つるぎ)だ
A spirit arts user, are you?
精霊術師デスか…
How truly... How truly...
どこまでも 本当にどこまでも…
これも あなたの筋書き
Is this also part of your plot?
I have never known such humiliation!
これほどの屈辱を
私は知らないのデス！
Really? Well, make the most of it.
そうか 存分に堪能してくれ
That's your bill for all you've done.
それが お前の
してきたことのツケだよ
Let's do it, Julius.
やるぜ ユリウス
Are you sure?
いいのだね？
I won't back down, I won't bend, I can't lose.
引かねえ 曲げねえ 負けられねえ
もう 誰も失いたくねえ
I don't want to lose anyone else.
I am the man who brutally beat you.
私は 君をひどく打ちのめした男だ
I still believe my behavior was
backed by meaning and reason,
あの行いに 私なりの理由と意義が
あったと 今も信じているが―
but that is no more than self-justification,
それは 君にとって関係のない
独善的なものにすぎない
which has nothing to do with you.
Can you trust me?
君は私を 信じられるのだろうか
I hate you.
（スバル）
俺は お前が大嫌いだ
Yes, I know.
ああ 知ってるとも
Having someone break your arms
and legs like that is traumatic.
手足折られて
普通に考えりゃ トラウマだぞ
Don't you know the meaning of restraint?
手加減知らねえのか？ てめえ
Just so you know, I did hold back quite a bit.
言っておくが あれでも
だいぶ手を抜いていたよ
Seriously? That was you holding back?
マジか 手加減してあれか
You really are the kind of guy I hate the most.
やっぱお前 最高にイヤな奴だ
I can hardly stand the sight of you, greatest knight.
俺はお前が大嫌いだよ
“最優”の騎士
So...
だから―
I will trust you.
お前を信じる
My shame attests to my knowledge
that you are an incredible knight.
お前がすげえ騎士だってことを
俺の恥が知ってるからだ
Then, with all my soul...
（ユリウス）
ならば 私は全霊で―
I shall live up to that!
それに応えよう
Is this farce over yet?
（ペテルギウス）
もう 茶番はよろしいデスか
What do you expect adding a single
spirit arts user to your ranks will do?
精霊術師１人加わったところで
何ができるというのデスか
I will pass judgment upon you both,
tear apart those who remain,
あなた方を下し
残る者どもを八つ裂きにし―
and resume the Ordeal. That is all.
試練を再開するだけのこと
My diligence knows neither
slothful resignation nor demise!
我が勤勉さに 怠惰な諦めも
終焉も ないのデス！
Sloth! Sloth! Sloth!
怠惰怠惰怠惰！ 怠惰ー！
Sloth!
Al Clarista!
アルクラリスタ！
（ペテルギウス）
ハハハハカカカッ… うっ
You... You should not be able to see it.
あなたは… あなたには
見えてないはずデス
見えていないはずデス
It should be invisible to you.
My Unseen Hand can be... seen?
見えざる手が見え… 見える？
No, it can't!
見えるはずが…
見えてたまるものか！
You shouldn't be able to see it!
And not by one, but two...
Two other people than me!
私以外に
ふたっ ２人も！
I'm the only one who can see it, Petelgeuse.
（スバル）
見えてるのは 俺だ
ペテルギウス
Huh!?
Julius can only see what I'm seeing.
（スバル）
ユリウスは
俺の見てる光景を―
見ているだけだよ
It also feels much creepier than I expected.
思った以上に
気持ち悪い感覚だけどな
I can use Nect to consciously share your senses,
ネクトで 意識的に
感覚の一部を共有し―
as well as to maintain them for a while.
維持することも できるはず
When you first proposed this,
I questioned your sanity.
君から最初 この案を
持ちかけられた時は―
正気を疑ったものだが
It worked, didn't it?
ちゃんとできただろ？
A man's all about guts.
男は度胸
何でもやってみるもんさ
You've gotta be open to anything.
フン
Curse you, curse you...
おのれおのれ…
Curse you! Curse you! Curse you! Curse you!
おのれおのれ
おのれおのれ！
Curse you!
おのれー！
お前と運命共同体ってのも
ゾッとしねえ
Sharing a body with you
like this makes me feel sick.
Let's get this over with.
とっとと終わらせようぜ！
Yes, let's.
ああ そうしよう
君の目で 私が切ろう
Using your eyes, I shall slay him...
My friend, Natsuki Subaru!
我が友 ナツキ･スバル！
The  Self-Proclaimed Knight
and the  Greatest Knight